JINESHWAR KHATRI

AHMEDABAD, GUJARAT 382481 | 9426570878 | jineshwarkhatri241198@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Perceptive and logical data analyst with proven ability to communicate with both technical professionals and clients to identify and translate business requirements. 2 years of experience in business intelligence, data analytics, and data warehousing and machine learning models.

Skills

Data Analysis: Python, R, SPSS, MS Excel, Data Preprocessing, Scikit Learn, Data Validation

Data Visualization: Power BI

ETL: SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS)

Database: MSSQL

Documentation: MS PowerPoint, MS Word

Work Experience

Data Analyst Intern, *Trellance, Ahmedabad, Gujarat Feb 2020 – Aug 2020*

- Worked on understanding different types of data and prepared proper documentation of data
- Identified and reported any data issues, conducted detailed weekly reports, and pro-actively participated in team meetings with managers.
- Developed the BI Suite for an assigned credit union using Power BI
- Created reports that accurately measure performance of the business, products and customers, ensuring business information needs are met.
- Automated the data loading process using SSIS & SQL Server
- Developed the detailed analyzer for credit card & auto loan portfolio and help organization in converting it into the standard products

Data Analyst, *Trellance, Ahmedabad, Gujarat Aug 2020 – Current*

SPSS

- Created the cross-sell model for auto loan using Decision Tree and identified the behavior having highest propensity to adopt the auto loan
- Created clustering model using K-Means to divide the customers into different segments by their past behavior

R Programming

- Developed the propensity model using Logistic Regression and gathered the product wise propensity score for all the customers. Further, identified the top 3 products to opt by their propensity score
- Developed the stepwise regression model for some important business metrics of credit union.
 Identified the most correlated macroeconomic variables for those business metrics and predicted the value of target variable(business variable) for next quarter

SSIS

- Developed new ETL packages, maintain, support and improve the performance of existing packages in production using SSIS.
- Deploy, automated, scheduled, and set up email notifications for daily data loading process using SSIS.

Power BI

- Created Credit card, Debit card & ACH transaction reports that accurately measure performance of the business and providing the detailed analysis of the transactors
- Created Enterprise Risk Management report using NCUA data which helps credit union to track their performance metric and analyze the same for the peers
- Further, added the Macroeconomic & Census data to the report to analyze the effect of it on credit union business metrics
- Performed the Scenario Analysis that shows the reaction of business variables on upcoming quarters by the change of its related Macroeconomic variable
- Presented the **Enterprise Risk Management** report to other teams and helped them to implement it for different credit unions

MSSQL

- Recommended strategies and plan of action to improve the campaign performance and reduce the campaign cost by targeting the members based on their behavior.
- Standardized the SQL queries, procedures and SSIS Packages to improve the performance and better optimization.
- Worked on the automated recurring transaction identification to take proactive action and communicate with their members and help them with the credit card conversions

• Worked on the data mapping and data creation part to combine two different data sources for all the analytics and reporting projects.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Engineering

August 2016 – May 2020 Silver oak college of engineering & technology, Ahmedabad CGPA – 8.22

Certifications

Data Science Training Program Fingertips, Ahmedabad

Master DAX for Power BI Issued by Udemy